<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pika Investing</title>
    <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pika Investing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter VII: REIT</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Wanting to invest in property but unable to due to high barrier of entry? Fret not!
Ever heard of REIT? Real estate investment trusts are company that own and manage a portfolio of income-generating properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter VI: Paralysis by Analysis</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Analysis paralysis describes an individual process when overanalysizing or overthinking a situation can cause forward motion or decision making to become paralyzed, meaning that no solution or course of action is decided upon. The keyword here is: Less is more.
There are 3 kinds of investing strategies: growth investing, dividend investing and value investing.
The ratios vary from industry to industry hence it is important to compare ratios for companies within the same industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter V: Profitability and Valuation</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Profitability ratio tells you how good a company is at converting business operations into profits. Valuation ratio is being used to get an idea whether a stock price is reasonable or not.
Some examples of these ratios: a. ROA b. ROE c. profit margin d. price to earnings e. price to book f. dividend yield</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter IV: Liquidity and Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Liquidity and debt ratios indicate how capable a business is in meeting its short term obligations as well protecting the long term health of its business. Efficiency ratios measure its ability to use what it has to generate profits. It can also reflect how effective the management is.
Some examples of these ratios: a. current ratio b. quick ratio c. debt to equity ratio d. interest coverage ratio e. asset turnover ratio f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter III: How do we pick stocks</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>There are more than tons of thousand methods of stock picking but it all come down to TWO basic analyses: fundamental analysis and technical analysis.
Fundamental analysis [FA] is a way trying to understand better the companies and their business models. We want to look at its business fundamentals such as the financial ratios. We also want to measure its business based on its past, current and future performance. This can be done by looking at their financial statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter II: The Zero Sum Game: Juggling Work and Life</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The conflicting demands of work and personal life have always been with us. People have always had children and elderly parents to care for; they have always pursued hobbies and devoted time to community activities. In the past, many managers dealt with such personal needs summarily: “What you do in the office is our business. What you do outside is your own.” It was assumed, too, that employees would put the company’s interests first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter I: The FIRE(d) Guide</title>
      <link>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edisondeng9.github.io/pika/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Financial Independence, Retire Early (FI/RE) is a movement dedicated to savings (sometimes extreme) and investment that allows its followers to achieve financial freedom and early retirement far earlier than traditional retirement plans.
Some proponents of the FIRE movement have retired as early as age 30, instead of the conventional and agreed upon retirement age of 65.
Steps to Achieving FIRE
In recent years, I’ve seen more and more Malaysians embracing the FIRE movement, especially the millennials.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
